<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:oai.datacite.org:1623376</identifier>
    <datestamp>2016-07-07T23:53:53Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>ANDS</setSpec>
    <setSpec>ANDS.CENTRE-1</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>Water Loss - Evaporation Reduction : data</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Lemckert, Charles</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Griffith University</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.4225/01/513D5A4AD7D62</dc:identifier>
      <dc:description>Other</dc:description>
      <dc:description>Approximately 300 GL of water evaporates from water storages in South East Queensland (SEQ) each year: roughly equal to urban water use in SEQ. This means two units of water need to be collected and stored for each unit of water supplied. There is consequently much benefit to be gained through the development and application of techniques for reducing evaporation. This dataset contains measurements of change in water height, humidity, air temperature, wind velocity and direction, surface water temperature and water temperature, which were collected within the Griffith University engineering laboratory (G09 1.40) in the wave tank enclosure. The wave tank is set up with the instruments at prescribed locations. The wind sonic, wind velocity probes, vaisala humidity probes and tough sonic distance sensor are connected to a DBK202 data logger which records and stores the data using Dasylab software. The radiometer and water temperature probes are connected to a CR100 data logger and the data is recorded and saved by LoggerNet software. The EasyLogger has an internal memory which stores the air temperature and humidity and can be downloaded post-experiment using EasyLog software. The experiment is run for a prescribed time defined by a starting and finishing time, which is manually synschronised between DasyLab, LoggerNet and EasyLog. Once an experiment is completed the EasyLog data is downloaded using the associated software, and the Dasylab and LoggerNet data is automatically saved as an ASCII file to a specified location. Using Matlab, these files are combined into one Excel (.xls) file.</dc:description>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
