<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:oai.datacite.org:1623580</identifier>
    <datestamp>2016-07-08T01:24:26Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>ANDS</setSpec>
    <setSpec>ANDS.CENTRE-1</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
    <oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
      <dc:title>Main externalities associated with desalination - Existing study details</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Daniels, Peter</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Griffith University</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
      <dc:identifier>doi:10.4225/01/513E55AA9A943</dc:identifier>
      <dc:description>Other</dc:description>
      <dc:description>This dataset is one of seven datasets that analyses a water supply option in terms of externalities (positive and negative effects that are not taken into account directly in market-place transactions). The water service option covered in this dataset is desalination, which involves removing the salt from seawater (or brackish groundwater) to make it useable for a range of purposes, including drinking. Related datasets cover stormwater harvesting, dams,wastewater recycling, groundwater, greywater and rainwater tanks. Each dataset identifies the social, environmental and economic impacts associated with the option in general and for each stage in its life cycle. Stages generally comprise the collection, storage, treatment, distribution of water and, finally, the decommissioning of the water supply option. The externalities were identified by an extensive survey of existing research and literature in water-related studies and through technical analysis of the option characteristics and technologies. The literature is vast and, at times, contradictory. The data is intended to provide an overview of the externalities that must be considered in the externality evaluation process, and does not provide not definitive values for option impacts as externality impacts will be site-specific.</dc:description>
    </oai_dc:dc>
  </metadata>
</record>
